Delwath: It's really a force of nature.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: It's like Delwath-
DM: Oh, yeah
Delwath: ... Pass force of nature, not
Unknown: Delwath-
DM: Where, where Seeker is just a Seeker leviathan.
Unknown: Right.
DM: 'Cause you retain your mental abilities, of course.
Unknown: But that's okay.
Unknown: And beard.
Unknown: Yeah, and beard.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Obviously. Oh, we need an...
Unknown: Okay, here.
Unknown: Im- important.
DM: Mike can be a crab leviathan if you want.
Kenzo: Also, what time did we wanna try to go watch the sunset?
Unknown: Although-
Unknown: Um
Unknown: ... it's looking pretty cloudy out.
Delwath: It is pretty cloudy, but the sun sets, like, at 5:45, so we should-
Unknown: Maybe like an hour, hour
Unknown: ... we should, like-
Unknown: All right
Delwath: ... give ourselves... We should leave 4:45.
Delwath: Maybe a few m- like 4:30, like an hour and a half maybe, we sort of, we sort of-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... take a break.
Unknown: Perfect.
DM: [sighs]
Unknown: [sighs]
DM: Yeah, that was, yeah, 4:30 is when I wanna stop so we can-
Unknown: Awesome [laughs].
Unknown: Perfect
DM: ... we can drive down.
Unknown: Perfect.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
DM: Okay.
DM: So we're not, I don't think we're gonna quite finish this before.
Unknown: No, that's fine.
DM: We'll do a little bit.
Delwath: Maybe we can at least, hopefully we can at least, uh, kill the one in the river.
Kenzo: Exactly, yeah.
Delwath: Then see what happens.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Kenzo's ready.
DM: So you pass through the, nobody has to bother making saves because-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... um, the...
DM: Uh, so you're just, you're just going upriver basically, right?
Delwath: No, that's not gonna work. You can't really make it bigger.
Unknown: Oh, you can. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I've given you a challenge.
Kenzo: B- b- before this is done, we'll, [laughs] we'll see how much bigger I can actually...
Kenzo: 'Cause I can see you've already pulled out some of the things that make it bigger.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: I love it.
DM: Okay, so let me-
Kenzo: Just a little bit
Unknown: more
DM: ... uh, so we'll put the river like this.
DM: You gotta-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... put this close here
Unknown: ... I'm moving it all.
DM: I don't need this guy.
DM: So here's, like, where the river bank runs roughly.
DM: And, you know, there's a few, like,
DM: still remaining...
Delwath: Wait, which, um, can...
DM: This is river.
Delwath: Oh, this, okay, this is the river.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: This is, yeah, okay.
DM: And you're coming, you come upriver.
Unknown: [laughs] That's ridiculous.
DM: And
DM: as you approach-
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
DM: ... so you're, you're limited to
DM: roughly-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Sorry. [laughs] It's silly.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: What do you even... No.
Kenzo: It's an accurate representation of Kenzo.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Okay.
DM: Um,
DM: so-
Unknown: Oh, shit
DM: ... you, the visibility is only 30 feet.
DM: And as you begin to go,
DM: go upriver, um,
DM: you sense,
DM: uh,
DM: you know, Kenzo, I'm just gonna let you be sort of attuned to this condensation.
DM: And you sense that it is, it is retreating as you move until you get close to the plaza.
Kenzo: Oh, what the fuck is this?
Kenzo: Oh, my God.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: What is happening?
Unknown: Uh...
Kenzo: No way.
DM: Uh, when,
DM: um,
DM: lunging from
DM: the shore into the river, you see this massive shape
DM: emerging in the distance.
Delwath: Wait, where was the thing in the river?
DM: Mm, there.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: They're temporary condensations in the morning.
DM: As you fly up, it re-
Unknown: Whoa
DM: ... it's retreating from the river, pulling back, and then
DM: leaps out at you,
DM: just condensing on the ground, rushing across the terrain here.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Wait, are we fighting this or is this the terrain?
DM: That, that's the ooze.
Unknown: What?
DM: So it's-
Seeker: Hold on a second. Were, were we already leviathaned up?
DM: Well, presumably-
DM: You have plenty of time to do whatever you wanna do here.
Unknown: Right. Huh.
DM: [coughs]
Seeker: So where, where are we supposed to be?
DM: Well, you're coming up the river from here.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, my God.
DM: I don't know how you're traveling.
Unknown: Well...
Unknown: Careful.
Delwath: Wellby and Kenzo are presumably f- Wellby can fly, right?
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: So I assume at some point we get into the river.
DM: River, you leviathan, you fly.
Unknown: Right?
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And we're just swimming in the river.
DM: So the two leviathans are swimming in the river.
Delwath: I mean, we might be a little further over.
Seeker: All right, so I'll mark down my-
DM: The-
Unknown: ... my level slot
DM: ... Wellby and Kenzo...
Kenzo: Dude, just be careful. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Just-
Unknown: Watch the stat. Yeah. [laughs]
DM: If you, if this falls over, Kenzo also falls prone.
Unknown: No.
Delwath: No, he's astral. He can't fall prone.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right. Kenzo is astral form already.
DM: Um, Wellby is-
Unknown: Wellby form
DM: ... Wellby form, but flying with your wings out from your...
DM: And you can s- you see this, your visibility is only 30 feet, so, um,
DM: uh, because of the intensity of the ash storm.
DM: So you can't actually see all of the ooze.
DM: You just see this, like, amorphous shape.
DM: You can see little bits of stone mixed into it.
DM: There's, like, sort of greenish tendrils coming out on the edges.
Wellby: I think, can we, like, gust of wind it or otherwise, like...
Wellby: I guess it doesn't matter if it's visible.
Seeker: Well, the leviathans have a tidal wave attack.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs] Awesome.
Seeker: Which is 250 feet.
DM: And it's-
Unknown: No.
DM: You can, like, it's-
Seeker: 250, 250 feet long
DM: ... this is, this is, like, just a massive thing that's, like, creeping.
DM: It seems like it's creeping along.
Delwath: Right. So, like, I'm trying to figure out, can we- Like the leviathan tidal wave attack is 120 feet
Delwath: and then goes for 250 feet
Seeker: So we could do it from far, far away.
DM: Except you can only see 30 feet away.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: You can only do it from 30 feet.
DM: Your visibility is 30 feet because of the ash.
Seeker: Right. But we could just retreat pretty far and then send out multiple tidal waves.
Delwath: Wow, it only recharges on a six, so-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... you're probably not gonna get that many unless we're lucky.
Seeker: Well, we can get two.
Delwath: We can get two.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: But we also have to... It can only be created,
Unknown: uh...
Delwath: Right, okay. So it...
Delwath: We'd probably be hard to target it until we can see the point.
Unknown: Also-
Delwath: I think it's Tim's point
Seeker: ... also there's no way for
Seeker: the humanoids to escape from it unless they're in the air, I guess.
Unknown: They're flying.
Unknown: They're up there. Okay.
Delwath: It's up to 250 feet tall, which generally in D&D terms means you don't have to make it that big.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Right?
Seeker: We can make a two-dimensional tidal wave.
Unknown: Yeah, it could just be narrow.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Right? It's up to 250 feet long and up to 250 feet wide.
Delwath: It can just be, it can just be 50 by 50.
Seeker: It's a little tidal wave bullet.
Delwath: It's very strong.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: Right?
Delwath: So it's gonna have a good strength saving throw.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But that's okay.
Unknown: So
Unknown: what are you gonna do?
Kenzo: We, we gotta go for it.
DM: I mean, I guess you better roll initiative-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... because you, you can't see it until you're within 30 feet of it anyway.
DM: The massive ooze lurking on the shore
Unknown: in wait.
Delwath: What is the leviathan's initiative plus seven?
Seeker: Oh, wait, so do I use my initiative?
Delwath: You use the li- leviathan's.
Unknown: 12.
Kenzo: 23. 18.
Unknown: Uh, uh...
DM: Sorry, 18... Who rolled an 19?
Unknown: Seeker?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: 23?
Kenzo: 23 for Kenzo. 22 for Wellby.
DM: Mike, what did you roll as well? Uh, 12.
Delwath: 13. No, 12.
Delwath: Can't do math.
DM: Okay. So the ooze goes first
DM: and it is going to turn, seeing you approach,
DM: slip into the water.
Unknown: We're flying.
Unknown: Um,
DM: yes. And then,
Unknown: uh,
DM: the first thing it's going to do,
DM: uh, is send
DM: pseudopod attacks
Unknown: against
DM: Del- uh, the two flying creatures.
DM: So two against Kenzo.
Unknown: That's a
DM: 21 and a 25.
Kenzo: Oh, only one hits.
DM: So, uh, you take 18 points of bludgeoning.
Kenzo: Uh, deflect attack.
DM: Plus nine points of...
DM: or 11 points of acid. Go ahead and reflect.
Kenzo: Wait, so how much is that total?
Unknown: Leviathan is so good against this.
Delwath: It's doing bludgeoning and acid.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Resistant to bludgeoning and immune to acid.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: I assume immune to acid.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Because leviathan
Unknown: does acid damage.
Kenzo: Oh, how much damage is that total?
Seeker: Yeah, but we're not gonna use that.
Unknown: 18 and...
Delwath: So it's like 32 total.
Kenzo: 32 total.
Kenzo: Aw, I did not cover it.
Kenzo: So I just reduce the damage by
Kenzo: 13 plus seven, 20.
Kenzo: I reduce it by 20.
DM: N- no. I don't think that's right.
DM: Don't you reduce the damage by plus your level?
Kenzo: Oh, a 1d10-
Unknown: 1d10 plus
Kenzo: ... plus 27. Ah.
Unknown: Plus 10.
Kenzo: Oh, ah, that's way better.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, I totally did.
Unknown: Sorry.
Unknown: 37.
DM: That damage you rolled is the damage you do when you deflect the attack.
Kenzo: Got it. Okay. Yeah, so 37.
Kenzo: I, I deflected it all. Hell yeah.
Unknown: Great.
DM: Okay. So it...
DM: Are you... You're deflecting I assume.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: So it has to make a dex saving throw.
Kenzo: Yeah, DC 20.
Unknown: Fails.
Kenzo: Sweet. So I just did-
DM: So what was that?
Unknown: What did you roll for the-
Unknown: 13.
Unknown: 20.
Unknown: 20 damage.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: So-
Unknown: Oh my God
DM: ... it takes 20 damage.
DM: Uh, except it's deflects...
DM: When you deflect it does the same
DM: damage as it did, right? So it doesn't take the acid damage from its own attack.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Oh, no, wait. No, no, no, it's new damage.
Unknown: What does it say?
Kenzo: Of the same type dealt by the attack.
DM: Yeah, so half of it is bludgeoning, half of it is acid.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So it only takes half. It only takes 10 damage.
Kenzo: [laughs] I'm, I'm tracking my key, Tim.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um...
DM: So then it's gonna make a pseudopod attack on Wellby.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: That's a 20 to hit.
Wellby: That just barely missed me.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: So you take, uh, 20 points of bludgeoning plus eight points of acid, so 28 total.
Wellby: Uh, I'll uncannily dodge that.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Is this 14?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Uh, and that's gonna end its turn. Okay.
Delwath: I'm gonna take a legendary action to move my move.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Seeker, do you want to go legendary action too?
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Oh my God, this is gonna be ridiculous.
Seeker: Is there an advantage to, I say telepathically to my other leviathan friend, to us spreading out?
Unknown: Water good. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Ooze bad.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: Kill Delwath only has a two intelligence.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Oh, sorry I asked.
Unknown: I'll, uh,
Seeker: I'll just go right over here.
DM: So also a legendary.
DM: Uh, so Kenza's up now.
DM: You are 30 feet away from the ooze up in the air.
Unknown: So-
Seeker: We have a 20-foot reach
Unknown: ... yeah
Seeker: ... which should be like that.
Delwath: Yeah, I'm like, yeah, I'm...
Unknown: Uh...
DM: I assume you're like underwater at this point.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah, swimming in the water.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Is this, is this in the water right now as well?
DM: It's half in the water, half out of the water.
Kenzo: Okay, cool. Yeah, I'll attack the part that's not in the water with this.
DM: Yeah, I mean, it's like 50 feet or like 80 feet across or something, so there's a lot of space you can attack.
Kenzo: Sol side first.
DM: Um-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... okay.
Seeker: I might wanna be further away because...
DM: So it's immune to acid damage as expected.
DM: Um, charmed, exhausted, frightened-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... grappled, poisoned, prone, restrained.
Kenzo: Yeah, we do all that stuff.
DM: You got all that. Um...
Unknown: Resistances?
DM: Uh, no resistances.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's good at...
DM: S- strength is its best save.
Unknown: [laughs] So intensive.
DM: Int is its worst save.
Kenzo: Int is its worst?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um...
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Int is its worst save, interesting.
DM: What else can we learn?
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: I never actually... This is... I never actually calculated the CR for this.
Unknown: It doesn't matter.
DM: It's a high CR.
Delwath: So it's basically immune to all conditions.
Delwath: It's, it's actually quite similar to a leviathan.
DM: It is, yeah. [laughs]
Delwath: Uh, immune to what? Acid and poison?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Acid and poison.
Delwath: But no resistances.
DM: No, no additional resistances-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... beyond the damage it inflicts.
DM: Okay. Kenzo's flying in to punch it.
Delwath: [coughs] You should, um, you should bring up your half dam- half resistance.
Unknown: Yeah. Um-
DM: Your damage resistance, I mean.
Kenzo: Yeah, so T- Kenzo will spend three ki on superior defense.
Kenzo: And then, um, I think it's worth it to do the, the, the langau's claw.
Delwath: It adds a D6.
Unknown: Extra D6, yeah.
Delwath: This could... Actually, this could stretch for a while.
Unknown: It is probably worth it.
Kenzo: All right. So I'll bonus action langau's claw.
DM: How long does it last?
Unknown: Uh-
DM: It lasts for an hour, right? Or does it last for...
Unknown: I thought it lasts for a minute.
Kenzo: Yeah, I, I think it's more of like a minute.
DM: Okay. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: One minute.
DM: Yeah, but that's 10 rounds. That's worth it.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. I'll do that.
DM: And then you make your staff attacks.
Kenzo: So two s- two staff attacks.
Kenzo: Uh, no, no advantage or anything, right?
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: Uh, 21 and something really high.
DM: 21 just hits.
DM: Something really high obviously hits.
Kenzo: All right. So those both hit, and then
Kenzo: I do... Oh, wow, D12 plus 9.
Kenzo: Okay, so now I do 3 D12.
DM: 3 D12 plus 18.
Kenzo: Plus 18, yeah.
Kenzo: Where are the D12s? [paper rustling] Uh, 18-
DM: Plus 18, 36.
Unknown: 36.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Uh, at the end of your turn, it will use a legendary action.
Unknown: A what?
DM: Um...
Delwath: How do you resolve two creatures trying to use a legendary action at the same time?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: That's... [laughs]
Wellby: Initiative order, I guess.
DM: Initiative order.
Unknown: I guess initiative. So it goes Delweth and then Kenzo.
DM: It goes Delweth, then Kenzo, yeah.
DM: 'Cause I'm also using a legendary action.
DM: So again, it hasn't noticed the two leviathans yet.
Delwath: Has Ken- uh, Kenzo hasn't gone yet.
Unknown: I mean-
DM: Kenzo just went. Wellby's next.
Delwath: Sorry. Okay, no, I'm gonna hold my action then.
DM: Uh, you both, uh, Kenzo and Delwath make dexterity saving-
Unknown: Wellby third, then Wellby.
DM: Sorry. Wellby and, and Kenzo make dexterity saving throws as a globule of acid shoots off his back and then explodes at a point in the air right about there.
Unknown: Uh-
DM: Re-roll.
Kenzo: I rolled a one, but I, I'm gonna...
Kenzo: I, I can spend a ki to re-roll it.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: 28 for me.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: 18.
DM: That does not succeed.
Kenzo: Uh, I will use a...
Kenzo: Bardic inspiration?
DM: Do we... We don't have any.
Delwath: Do we have... Did we give out Bardics?
Delwath: We probably should have given everybody a Bardic.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: We always give out-
Unknown: Ooh
DM: ... a Bardic.
DM: Okay, okay. Everybody has...
DM: You all have Bardics.
Delwath: 'Cause you have, what, six total?
Unknown: I do.
DM: Yeah, so half.
Delwath: So that's everybody...
Delwath: Each of us has one, and then...
Kenzo: Is this like roll two and then pick the higher?
DM: No.
Delwath: Nope, nope, roll one.
Unknown: Okay. [die rolling] Uh, 26.
DM: Okay, that succeeds.
DM: So both of you dodge out of the way of the massive burst of acid that explodes, avoiding getting drenched in dripping acidic poison ooze.
Kenzo: That sounds like a good thing that we did.
DM: And that ends its legendary action.
DM: Any other legendary actions?
Delwath: No, I'm waiting till after, 'cause you'll give us advantage on attacks, right?
DM: Um-
Delwath: Wait. No, no. Uh, Eric, once Wellby attacks, we both should do our legendaries to do a slam attack.
DM: Oh, okay.
Delwath: Because we'll have advantage from Wellby's...
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Great.
DM: So Wellby, you're up.
Unknown: And that costs two anyway, but that's fine.
Wellby: The entire creature counts as one creature for the purposes of a second sneak attack.
Wellby: It's not like-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... a tentacle is a different thing.
DM: Right. Yeah, no, it counts as one creature.
Wellby: Yeah. Uh, re-rolling one.
Wellby: [die rolling] That's a 28 or something like that.
DM: That hits. A 21 to Kenzo.
Kenzo: 21, yeah.
DM: So...
Wellby: I think it is resistant to every single special thing that I can do.
DM: I think it is too.
Wellby: Um, so I'm just gonna...
Wellby: 3, 6, 9,
Wellby: 10.
Wellby: [dice rattling] [die rolling] Uh, 5, 10, 20, 30, uh, 35, 43.
Wellby: 43.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: is it-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... resistant to lightning?
DM: Uh, nope. It's just immune to acid and poison.
Delwath: It has no additional damage resistances.
Wellby: Uh, I may as well use the lightning arrow then in a second at- [die rolling] tack, which I have.
DM: You didn't use your bonus action for anything, so...
Wellby: Yeah. [die rolling] Uh, that's high 20s again.
DM: Yep. That's a dex save?
Wellby: Uh, these are 19 dex.
DM: Uh, it succeeds then.
Wellby: Uh...
DM: Oh wait, no
Wellby: Oh wait, wait. It's not a save for the target
DM: ... it doesn't... It's just the target-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... so it doesn't... It takes the... So it's-
Wellby: Okay, so it's nine regular damage
DM: And 4d6 lightning.
Wellby: Yep.
Wellby: Uh, eight, 10, 15 lightning.
DM: Okay.
DM: Got it.
DM: Is that the end of your turn?
Wellby: That is the end of my turn.
Delwath: Okay. Ken, there's no point in rolling the acid damage, right?
Unknown: It's immune.
DM: Yeah, it's immune to acid.
Wellby: Oh, actually, uh, I'm also...
Wellby: I'm gonna move to a place that's, like, 100 feet away and-
DM: Okay, so now you can't see it, though
Unknown: You can only see within 30 feet.
DM: Your visibility is only 30 feet because of the-
Wellby: Well, I'm gonna stay 30 feet...
Wellby: Oh, shit. Do we want to stay within visual seeing each other?
DM: I don't know if that matters.
Wellby: So I'm gonna stay 30 feet above it, but go, like, way to another part of it so that a single effect couldn't hit both Kenzo and I, hopefully.
DM: Okay. So-
Unknown: So you like-
DM: ... a huge fly around towards the back
Wellby: ... exactly
Delwath: ... a huge fist materializes from the water
Delwath: and slam, punches into the ooze.
DM: [dice rolling]
Seeker: Wait, how are you doing that?
DM: That's your action.
Delwath: Oh, but a 19 might miss.
DM: A 19 misses.
Unknown: No.
Seeker: Wait, that's its slam attack?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: You could do one, too.
Seeker: Uh, I'm doing that.
DM: Oh, so slam attack. Okay.
Unknown: Um-
DM: So now it knows you're here 'cause you're-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... slamming it.
Seeker: What do, what do I roll?
Delwath: That's... Well, you have advantage, so 2d20 and then add 14.
DM: So sorry, this is after Wellby's turn.
Unknown: Yep, 30.
DM: 30.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: So that hit, so it's 2d12,
Kenzo: 2d12 plus 8 damage.
Wellby: I have a thing at the end of your turn I just want to forget.
Delwath: So at the end of this. [dice rolling]
DM: So 26.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 26 damage?
Unknown: 26.
DM: And you're not rolling the acid, right?
Unknown: Correct.
DM: This is just-
Unknown: Yeah, that's, that's bludgeoning
DM: ... 2d12.
Delwath: It's 4d12 including acid where I'm-
DM: Okay
Unknown: ... rolling the bludgeoning. [dice rolling]
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh... [clears throat]
Unknown: Sweet.
DM: Wait, did it use its le-
Kenzo: It, it did. It used legendary.
DM: It used the le- it used legendary.
Delwath: It used a legendary action.
DM: Yeah. Got it.
Unknown: I don't know the-
Wellby: Wellby will say telepathically to the rest of us, "There's this tendril in back that's heading back towards the central plaza, like a,
Wellby: like a thing that's connecting it back to the center again."
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Let's stop that.
Wellby: Should we try and-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... cut it off?
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. Let, let's, let's stop that.
Seeker: What does Delwath's leviathan say?
Seeker: Does that say that?
DM: Gargoyle rocks.
Unknown: Ooze bad. [laughs]
DM: Kill ooze.
Delwath: Hurting water. Ooze hurting water.
Unknown: Kill ooze.
DM: Uh, it's Seeker's turn now.
DM: Your actual turn, not your legendary.
Unknown: Pretty smart.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Um, uh, maybe I go after that.
Seeker: I'm gonna cast a-
DM: Wellby?
Delwath: Oh, right. You can cast.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Pretty fast.
DM: Oh, yeah. I have to choose between-
Unknown: Oh, just the tendril?
Wellby: I think so
Seeker: ... it's basi- it's gonna be Rune of Psychic Destruction,
Seeker: which I will cast at...
Kenzo: This looks like a weird, like, sea urchin.
DM: Wait, you're up in the air, right?
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: And we're both like-
Wellby: Like 30 or 40 feet up
Seeker: ... I will cast at,
Seeker: let's say
Seeker: seventh level.
Kenzo: Each one of these squares is how many?
DM: Five.
Wellby: Five.
Unknown: Oh, five.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: so that's a DC 19 int save.
DM: It is its worst save [dice rolling] but it rolled a natural 20.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: So
Seeker: it's not incapacitated and then half-
DM: It's probably half damage
Seeker: ... so it's 10d6.
DM: Divided by two.
Seeker: Um, I'll just do that here.
DM: Yeah, and that's faster. [pens scribbling]
Seeker: 35 divided by 2.
Unknown: 18.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: 17. 17, rather.
DM: It's rounds down, so 17.
Unknown: Okay. [dice rolling]
DM: Uh, that, is that end of your turn?
Delwath: Uh, you get two attack... Oh, no, you're done with
DM: your turn.
Seeker: I could probably move also.
Delwath: [chair scraping] Yeah, and I'm done.
DM: Okay. Uh, and it's going to now use a legendary action.
DM: Um,
DM: so it is going to drop a...
DM: uh, falling around...
DM: Well, the rest of you can't see this.
DM: Kenzo, make a dexterity saving throw.
Kenzo: Wait, Kenzo or Wellby?
Unknown: That's Wellby.
Wellby: Oh, Wellby in the back. [dice rolling]
Wellby: 16.
DM: That fails.
Kenzo: All right. All right, well, Barric?
Wellby: Uh, I'll still only take half damage, so I'll...
Wellby: I'm gonna see how this is.
DM: Um,
DM: a, another globule of, of acid sprays,
DM: sprays towards you like a, like a fine, uh,
DM: string of nets-
Wellby: Mm
DM: ... wrapping around you,
DM: and you are now restrained.
Wellby: Ah.
DM: And you take, uh...
DM: The damage is poison, so you take no damage.
DM: Oh, you take a quarter damage because you are re-
Wellby: Resistant
DM: ... e- evasion plus resistance, so...
Kenzo: I feel like it's good to avoid these things, 'cause yeah, they're restraining, getting grappled-
DM: So you take eight points-
Unknown: ... getting knocked out
DM: ... of damage, but you are restrained-
Wellby: Which sets-
DM: ... which sets your move to zero and, um, you have disadvantage on all attacks, and all attacks against you have advantage
Wellby: ... is restrained the same or different from grappled?
Unknown: Grappled.
DM: It is different from grappled.
Wellby: So the advantage that I have to escape from grappled is not the same as advantage for restrained?
Kenzo: Does not the same as advantage for restrained.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Um, you get a save-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. It's 'cause they're gonna... You get knocked out, and then we have to spend time and-
DM: You get a new save at the end of every turn
Unknown: ...
Unknown: figure it out. Yeah.
DM: So at the end of your next turn, you can save to escape automatically.
Unknown: Who's up?
DM: Um, Delwath is up.
DM: That was the ooze's legendary unless-
Unknown: Whoa
DM: ... unless you want to take a... Oh, you're out of legendaries.
Delwath: Yeah, I got them back. Seeker can take a legendary.
DM: You can take a legendary after your own turn.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Right. Yeah, yeah,
Unknown: yeah.
DM: So it's very complicated with the number of legendary actions [laughs].
Unknown: Yeah, it's insane. Yeah.
Unknown: Um...
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: Oh, so I think the pseudo-
Seeker: So I had to do some memory reset.
Delwath: Do we think the pseudopod can be broken?
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Do you think the what?
DM: Do you have some idea?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Well, I'm gonna try.
Kenzo: Kenzo's gonna fly over here too and try to break this thing off here.
Delwath: Right. I'm, I'm gonna send a tidal wave right here.
Delwath: Originator tidal wave, like, here, and just go this way.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Trying to wash away the-
DM: That's a strength saving throw?
Delwath: D- yeah, it's a DC 24 strength save.
DM: Uh, that's a 25.
DM: So it takes half damage?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Or half of...
Unknown: My bounce savitates.
DM: Can you, can you grab a bowl over there for me so I can put some chips in it?
Unknown: Watch your hands.
Kenzo: You want these chips?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: It's a crappy, crappy, crappy roll.
Unknown: 10...
DM: And this is Bludgeoning?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, 10,
Delwath: mm, uh, 21.
Delwath: [laughs] Man, that's like minimum damage.
Unknown: 22.
DM: So 11 'cause it made the save?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Okay. Geez.
Unknown: That's three ones.
DM: That's certainly not enough. Whether or not the pseudo pod thing-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... can be destroyed, that's certainly enough to at least...
Kenzo: Dude, it should be Delweth. Delweth can, like, smite and do stuff.
Delwath: I know. Wow, I rolled like three ones.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: 7 to 12 is actually pretty good.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: It's solid.
DM: Um,
DM: at the end of Delweth's turn, it's gonna use its last legendary action to just make a pseudopod attack against Wellby with advantage.
DM: I mean, that's a 30-something.
Kenzo: Well, legendary actions are good too, then.
Delwath: I might be calling Delweth. I'm trying to get it to, like, attack me-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... do 300 points of damage, and then I'll turn back into Delweth with full hit points.
DM: Uh, 4 plus 18, so 22 total damage.
Unknown: That would be good.
Unknown: I mean...
Wellby: Yep.
DM: So that is after Delweth's turn.
DM: Now we're back up to its start, it- its turn again.
Kenzo: You have a legendary?
Seeker: I actually could do a legendary now, yeah.
DM: Yes, you could do a legendary.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Slam it.
Seeker: So I'll do my slam again.
Seeker: Ooh, a five and a four.
Unknown: Plus a-
Delwath: Um, do we still have advantage? Yes, until Wellby's turn.
Wellby: [sneezes]
DM: Until Wellby's turn you have advantage.
Delwath: That's gonna miss though. 19 misses.
DM: Yeah, 19 misses.
Kenzo: Okay. So that's just one attack?
Delwath: We only get one attack as legendary.
DM: All right.
Kenzo: Ah, yes.
DM: Yeah. Okay.
Seeker: Oh, and this is weird.
Seeker: It has water form. The leviathan can enter a hostile creature's space and stop there.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: So I could, like, go on top of it.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: And I could actually kind of go as far as I want, 'cause 120-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... in water-
Kenzo: Well, let's, we're trying to snap this tendril off-
DM: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... so try to do something here to...
Unknown: Oh, that's a good idea.
DM: Well, the water ends about in the middle of it.
Unknown: Here.
DM: It's like half in, half out.
Seeker: And then... But I still have 40 feet move
Seeker: on land.
DM: Yeah, so you could-
Seeker: I'll split my move and go here.
DM: Okay.
DM: So this massive leviathan crawls through the ooze-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... and then settles
DM: as a lake of water, pure water sort of on top, which it writhes and struggles against.
DM: And that is going to
DM: blast-
Delwath: Wait, who's... Oh, Kenzo's next, right?
DM: It's, its turn. It's gonna blast a line of acid that hits
DM: that, that hits Seeker Leviathan and Delweth.
DM: Uh, so-
Unknown: Well, at least we're immune to acid damage.
Unknown: Is that Wellby?
Kenzo: Or Seeker Leviathan and Wellby?
DM: And Wellby, yeah. Sorry.
Unknown: Is it acid damage?
DM: It is acid damage.
Delwath: Okay. Ha ha ha ha ha.
DM: Dexterity saving throw.
Delwath: We're immune to acid damage.
DM: For Wellby.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: With disadvantage because you're restrained.
DM: Yeah.
DM: S- not doing... It's not great against a levi- a leviathan [laughs].
Unknown: Uh, 18?
DM: Uh, that fails.
Unknown: Uh, Bardic.
Wellby: There you go.
Wellby: Uh, 26.
DM: 26 succeeds.
Wellby: There we go.
Delwath: That was a very hesitant succeeds on 26 [laughs].
DM: You take no damage.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: That's the end of its turn?
DM: No, that's just the first thing it did this turn.
DM: Oh, right. Okay. It's gonna make two attacks now.
Delwath: All right, can I just...
Delwath: The initiative order is-
DM: Kenzo-
Delwath: ... Kenzo, Wellby, Seeker, Delweth
Delwath: ... I just wanna do a legendary.
Delwath: Kenzo, Wellby...
DM: You can do a legendary after its turn.
DM: Its turn, yeah, after Kenzo's turn.
DM: Okay, perfect.
Unknown: Please.
Delwath: Uh, so it's gonna make two...
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It's clearly, um, angry at
DM: Wellby.
Wellby: It's pinned it.
Unknown: Bardic.
Delwath: You're like... It's not your weekend.
DM: It makes two attacks against Wellby, both with advantage.
DM: One hits, the other is a 21.
DM: Does 21 hit?
Wellby: Indeed it does.
Kenzo: What the fuck, man?
Kenzo: We've got these two huge ass leviathans.
Kenzo: I'm resistant to everything. Why are they fucking going after you, dude?
Unknown: Wellby.
Delwath: Possibly because [laughs] we're all resistant to its damage.
Kenzo: No, but it's in ooze. How does it know?
DM: I know, it shouldn't know. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Uh, sorry, that's 15 plus
DM: 9.
Wellby: Awesome.
DM: So 24 for the first hit.
Wellby: That's not bad.
DM: And then 15 plus
DM: 9. I rolled the exact same thing twice.
DM: Um, I mean, you might stop to think for like a second about why it might be, again, going against Wellby.
Delwath: Yeah, but he's the top of the pseudopod.
Wellby: Yes.
DM: Um...
Wellby: All right, I just lost half my hit points.
DM: That ends its turn.
Wellby: Most of one round.
Delwath: Okay, legendary action, move 120 feet to join my friend.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: All right [laughs].
DM: Uh, I don't know what it's gonna do about this.
Unknown: Leviathan friends
Unknown: be together.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Bite tail.
DM: Yeah, you get like a fri- like a-
Delwath: Delwath is radiating a sense of real anger about this thing 'cause, like, Delwath is identifying as the leviathan protector of nature here.
Delwath: Um, coming out of the water, this is an intrusion of the water.
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: We have to destroy it.
Delwath: And he's like, "This is my buddy, Smart Leviathan, who knows what to do, so I'm just gonna follow him."
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Smart. [laughs]
Seeker: Right. [laughs] I, I'm the l- I'm the nerd leviathan.
Unknown: Well, it's a tick. [laughs]
Kenzo: It's really obvious what's happening
Unknown: That wasn't legendary.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: All right. All right. Is Seeker doing any legendary actions?
Seeker: I think I burned mine all since my last turn.
Unknown: Oh, okay. So you need to then-
Unknown: I just went with the move, so
DM: ... wait until your turn. Okay, so now it's Kenzo's turn.
Kenzo: All right. Kenzo will, uh, move.
Kenzo: Uh, I, I've got 70 move, so I can easily get over here 'cause I'm gonna get into the action over on this side.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
Kenzo: And then, yeah, I'm, I'm gonna try to, uh, break, snap the tendril.
Kenzo: All right.
Kenzo: And now I get, uh, two staff attacks.
Kenzo: Is this advantage now or no? Just normal regular attack?
Unknown: And so Wellby's turn.
Delwath: You still have advantage till Wellby's turn, so advantage.
Kenzo: Oh, hell yeah. Okay, great.
Kenzo: So this is my first staff attack.
Kenzo: Uh, that hits and that d- Well, actually, let me, let me roll the two staff attacks.
Kenzo: Ah, okay, definitely. They both hit, and then I do...
Unknown: 3 12+.
Unknown: Plus two-
Unknown: 3 12
Kenzo: ... no, plus 2d6.
Unknown: Oh, the 1s.
DM: Yeah, but d6 is only for your punches, not-
Unknown: Ah
Kenzo: No, no, no, it's for any melee attacks.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Kenzo: Yeah. Uh, so it's this plus
Unknown: 16.
Delwath: Right? Or 18. 18.
Kenzo: Hold on. That's the wrong number still, which I started.
DM: It's some... It's 19 I think.
Unknown: No, it has to be
Unknown: an even number.
Kenzo: Yeah, 18 plus 8.
Delwath: Yeah, that's what I thought last turn was 18.
Unknown: 18.
Kenzo: These are just the staff attacks.
Unknown: Yep.
Kenzo: So is this...
Kenzo: Ooh, this is good.
Delwath: That's a good roll.
Kenzo: Oh, this is very good.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Uh, 22, 32, 37 plus 18 is 47, 55.
Unknown: So that's Kenzo-
Unknown: Two staffs
DM: ... coming down with the staff, like three, twice, like hammering on the pseudopod.
DM: Like, part of its,
Unknown: part of its-
Wellby: Can I break off a piece of this?
DM: No, no. Part of its body-
Unknown: Oh, no
DM: ... flows out from here-
Unknown: What?
DM: ... and reinforces.
Seeker: It reinforces. Oh.
Delwath: Ah, that's a cool mechanic.
Unknown: That's awesome.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
Delwath: It can flow hit points from itself to the pseudopod.
Unknown: Oh, boy. Okay.
Delwath: This thing probably has 1,000 hit points.
Kenzo: Oh, boy. Fun, fun, fun. All right.
Unknown: So I'm gonna do-
Delwath: All right. How much damage did you do?
Unknown: 55.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Um, now I'm gonna do my three punch attacks.
Unknown: Just... Yeah.
Kenzo: So, uh, first attack, that definitely hits.
Kenzo: Second attack. Ooh, natural 20, right?
Unknown: That's crazy.
Kenzo: And then third attack.
Kenzo: That still hits.
Kenzo: 20, 21. 21 hits.
Unknown: 21 hits, yep.
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay, that, that still hits. All right. So now I do...
Unknown: How much do-
Delwath: You do 4-
Unknown: Natural
DM: ... 40 12 plus 46 'cause they all hit.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: 40 12 plus 46.
Unknown: Plus 46.
DM: You get an extra d12 and an extra d6.
Delwath: Plus, um, and you do plus 7 instead of plus 9, right?
Kenzo: Correct. Plus 7 times 2.
Unknown: So plus 21.
Unknown: Plus 21.
Delwath: So 40 12 plus 46 plus 21.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Kenzo: Do a lot of damage now.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Level 20's pretty sweet.
Unknown: 46.
Unknown: Yeah, you need one more d12.
Unknown: Here.
Kenzo: 46 plus 40 12 plus what?
Unknown: 21.
Unknown: Plus 21.
Unknown: Ooh.
Kenzo: Yeah, plus 21. Cool.
Delwath: Man, you're doing good on the damage there.
Unknown: 15, 20,
Kenzo: uh, 30, 40.
Unknown: 40.
Unknown: Holy fuck.
DM: And move some stone back.
Kenzo: 40... Uh, what the fuck is this?
Unknown: Hardening.
Unknown: That's, um, 6 plus-
Kenzo: 50, 54
Kenzo: ... 54 plus-
Unknown: Plus
Delwath: ... 21. 60...
Unknown: 75.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Kenzo: Holy shit. That's the most I've ever done in a turn.
Unknown: So a-
Unknown: Damn.
DM: Sorry. Okay. After Kenzo...
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Holy shit.
Unknown: Uh...
Kenzo: Ad- Advantage Kenzo at 20 level monk is pretty nasty.
Unknown: Holy shit.
DM: So after Kenzo-
Unknown: I'm doing a ton of damage
DM: ... punches, a bunch of the stone
DM: in its body goes back and you find...
DM: And it's forming a s- like a stone barrier along this pseudopod.
Delwath: I'm gonna use a legendary action to...
Delwath: Another fist of water appears and slams into it, like right...
Delwath: 13. That'll hit. 25.
DM: Okay. Is this bludgeoning damage?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, is it resistant to bludgeoning damage now?
Seeker: Is this the kind of thing where the more damage we do to this thing, the stronger it gets?
Kenzo: I don't think so.
Unknown: 13.
DM: Um, the fist of water-
Kenzo: And if that was the case, I don't know if there's a way to, like-
DM: ... hits into the stone-
Unknown: ... do the opposite of that
DM: ... and the energy is partially dissipated-
DM: We, uh, damage ourselves
DM: ... along the line of the pseudopod. Sorry, how much was that?
Unknown: 13.
Wellby: It's not like a-
Unknown: Half
Unknown: ... desiccant
Unknown: ... 6
Wellby: ... spell or something like that.
Kenzo: Guys, I did 120 damage on, like, a regular attack.
Delwath: Ha. But the...
Delwath: If it gains resistance to bludgeoning damage, that it's now, like, gonna be hard for us to actually hurt it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Is it resistant to bludgeoning?
DM: Yeah. It's reinforced the pseudopod-
Unknown: It's, it just reinforced
DM: ... with the, all the stone.
Delwath: But you, you also do... Oh, no, you can do force damage.
Wellby: Why don't we just go further down?
Unknown: I can do force damage.
Wellby: I mean, if the pseudopod goes all the way back to the main square, why don't we just go down another
Wellby: 50 feet?
Delwath: And it's probably reinforcing the whole...
Unknown: Uh, yeah.
Unknown: Is it, is that the idea?
DM: The stone is filling out as far as you can see,
DM: which is only 30 feet.
DM: All right.
Unknown: Um, sorry.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I'm losing track. That was...
DM: It wants to do a legendary action.
Unknown: Wait, did you already do a legendary action?
Delwath: That damage was just my legendary.
DM: Okay. Well, that's fine. It's gonna do a legendary now before Seeker does a legendary action.
Unknown: Um...
Delwath: [laughs] This is a little ridiculous.
DM: It is. Uh, and
DM: man, immune to acid is really tough for it to do much against.
Unknown: That's why the devil-
DM: Oh, wait. Are you immune to poison?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Oh, wait. You are immune to poison.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: God damn it. Okay. [laughs]
Unknown: It can't really hurt us.
Kenzo: [laughs] Well- Outwitting the DM
Wellby: ... th- th- there's 25% of us.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Can't really hurt half of us.
Delwath: But this is really good for Seeker 'cause you can just cast your spells.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But actually-
Delwath: My attacks are getting less and less effective because it's all bludgeon, it's all damage it's also resistant to.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: So we're like two giants trading ineffective hits against each other.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Which is not-
Kenzo: I mean, not bad. I mean, I'm kind of okay with it
Delwath: If I could get it to attack me, that would be great.
Kenzo: That would be great.
DM: Kenzo is the... Kenzo just did a ton of damage along the pseudopod so Kenzo make a dexterity saving throw as more of this acid muck flies out towards you.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
DM: You-
Kenzo: Uh, I, I spent a ki in rerolling
DM: That's fantastic.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Well. So you are now...
DM: You take-
Unknown: 16.
DM: Yeah, that fails.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You take, um,
DM: 44 reduced by...
DM: Oh, double reduced because-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: You're-
Kenzo: Both immune and resistant.
DM: Right. So you take-
Unknown: 11
DM: ... 11 points of
DM: damage, but you are now also restrained.
Unknown: Ah.
Kenzo: So annoying.
DM: B- same as Wellby, so speed is zero, attacks against you have advantage,
DM: um, your attacks have disadvantage.
DM: At the end of your turn, you can make another save to escape.
Kenzo: Dude, how did I fail two fucking dex saves?
DM: That's... It's legendary.
Seeker: Are you fucking serious?
DM: Okay, Wellby's turn. Uh, unless Seeker wants to...
DM: Oh, no, Seeker's out of legendaries till his turn.
Unknown: That's right.
DM: So Wellby's up.
Unknown: Ugh.
DM: So your attacks have disadvantage until, uh...
DM: Oh, well, advantage-
Wellby: I have advantage from cancel
DM: ... so cancels out, so straight roll.
Wellby: Sure, well do I still get sneak attack because there's an ally within five?
DM: Yes. Yeah.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: Are you aiming for the main body or the tail?
Wellby: Uh, tail is not yet resistant to piercing damage.
DM: You think?
Wellby: Okay.
DM: You think it's only resistant to bludgeoning.
DM: It probably can't be resistant to multiple things at once.
Wellby: Uh, is it the same day as it was yesterday or is this...
Wellby: Do we long... We long rested since.
DM: Yeah. We did.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Oh, okay. Um, I'll use the clockwork amulet to roll a 24.
DM: That hits.
Wellby: And I will get some more dice.
Delwath: Um, is Delwath next?
DM: No, it's Seeker. Seeker, yes, then Delwath.
Wellby: Okay. All right.
Wellby: Five. Uh, 22, 25, 30-
DM: Sorry, you are a- you are shooting at the t- at the pseudopod
Wellby: ... 35. Yep. Uh,
Wellby: 39 plus 8 is 47.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: Can I get more bardic inspiration?
Wellby: Is that a... That's not a thing you can do in this form?
DM: Not as a leviathan you can't.
DM: Uh.
Wellby: Uh, and then save to escape grapple?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Or-
DM: Dex save to escape the restraint
Kenzo: ... restraint. You can only do it at the end of the turn.
DM: End of your turn.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Dex save?
DM: Dex save.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Seeker, you're up.
Wellby: Restrain... Yeah. That's weird that restrain is...
Wellby: No, it's not weird. Uh.
Seeker: I'm thinking about just psychic disruption again.
Wellby: 15 probably doesn't do it.
Unknown: Nope.
Wellby: Should I use my heroic?
Kenzo: Probably, man. You want to get the fuck out of this shit.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, 'cause it can keep hitting me.
Kenzo: This is like one of those, like, I feel like saves are just important to spend, you know, if you can get out of them.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Uh, 20?
DM: Nope.
Unknown: What?
Wellby: Oh, no. [laughs]
DM: Hey, their DC is 24.
DM: Why should its be any le- worse?
Wellby: Oh.
DM: That's rough.
Wellby: Uh, uh, because I rolled poorly is the answer.
DM: Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Damn.
Kenzo: It is very annoying.
DM: Um, but as your arrow strikes, um, the...
DM: Well, actually wait.
DM: That was at the end of your turn, so now it's gonna use its legendary.
Wellby: To release me from the restraint.
DM: Nope, to attack you.
Wellby: Oh, neat.
DM: You, you're noticing a pattern.
Wellby: Oh. Oh.
DM: It basically is just attacking whoever was the last one to do damage to its tail.
Wellby: Hold up. I'm gonna use my bonus action-
Unknown: Oh
Wellby: ... to get my second wind.
DM: Ah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Wellby: And regain three hit points.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: That's still more than zero hit points.
Wellby: That's right.
DM: So it has advantage on you.
DM: Um,
DM: two natural ones.
Unknown: Whoa. Wow.
DM: So with your second wind-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... you dodge out of the way. That's its legendary.
DM: Anybody else want to do legendaries?
Unknown: I'm out.
DM: Same. Okay. So-
Seeker: 'Cause it's about to be my turn
DM: ... so Seeker's up.
Seeker: I will try again another psychic disruption, this time at sixth level.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: it's like, uh, DC 19 and save.
DM: Uh, okay.
DM: Whoops.
DM: Um,
DM: it's gonna burn a legendary resistance.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And it hardens slightly, reducing its speed
DM: as it uses its legendary resistance, which seems like it may have no effect because everybody's crowded around it.
DM: Um.
Seeker: So I'll roll the 9d6 and we'll take half?
DM: Uh, yep.
Unknown: So that's-
DM: That's its first legendary that it's burned.
Seeker: 23 over two is
Unknown: 11.
DM: Yeah. Okay.
DM: And that's on the...
DM: That was your turn?
Delwath: Um, I, I guess I could also move if I want to, but I'm not sure the point.
DM: Yeah. Right. Okay.
Unknown: Can you cast spells?
DM: Yeah. Seeker can cast spells as a leviathan.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Delwath can't.
Unknown: 'Cause it's a shape changed version of a leviathan.
DM: Um,
DM: okay. Now it's gonna use, uh...
DM: It used, it's used two legendaries and it's actually gonna use its last legendary-
Kenzo: To attack Seeker
DM: ... No, 'cause it doesn't really recognize that spells are attacks.
Unknown: No.
DM: It can't tell what a spell attacks are.
Unknown: Is it gonna attack Wellby again?
DM: Yeah, 'cause Wellby's the last one that damaged it.
Kenzo: Damn it.
Wellby: Yeah, but I got those big three HP.
Kenzo: Ah, you did get that, that, that, that big three.
DM: Right?
Seeker: What's your total HP?
Wellby: I'm on 86 right now.
Unknown: Oh, you're fine.
DM: Well, that was a one.
DM: Uh, that was a 20...
DM: A 15, so it's...
DM: Sorry, an 8 plus 15 is 23.
Wellby: That's a hit.
DM: Okay. So
DM: that's gonna do
DM: 20 bludgeoning plus five acid, so 25 total.
Wellby: Whoa. Awesome.
Wellby: Yep. Good.
DM: That's its legendary. Seeker's turn is over.
DM: Delwath is up.
Seeker: Okay. Oh, I can do my legendary.
DM: After my... After Delwath.
Delwath: Delwath is gonna, like... Okay.
DM: You can't do legendaries after your own turn, after...
DM: only after somebody else's turn
Seeker: But wasn't it just its turn?
Unknown: No.
DM: No.
Unknown: That was it.
DM: It was its legendary [laughs].
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: That was you.
Kenzo: Its legendary.
Delwath: Thank you.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: Dalwath will like-
Kenzo: It's, it's just legendaries all the way down
Delwath: ... will like roar at it in anger.
Delwath: Like, like, you know, you're a terrible thing.
Delwath: Like, and form a sort of whirlwind of, um, of water that swirls around and just slams into it twice.
DM: The tail or the main body?
Delwath: The tail.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: But misses the first time.
DM: That misses.
Delwath: Uh, does 21 hit?
DM: 21 hits, yep.
Delwath: Hits the second time.
Delwath: Uh, so hits with the tail, which is less good but...
Delwath: Oh my God.
Delwath: For, for [laughs] 11 points of bludgeoning damage.
Seeker: We're doing
Seeker: peanuts to him right now.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: We need Kenzo to hit again or 10 times that.
DM: Um, 11. Okay, so-
Unknown: Six, five, six.
Unknown: I forget if you round up or down.
DM: You round down.
Unknown: I'm doing a lot of damage.
DM: Um, the...
DM: Even so, with that hit, even though it was weak, you can see cracks starting to form on the tail.
Unknown: All right. All right.
DM: Uh, that's gonna be its turn.
DM: It now turns in anger at Dalwath.
Unknown: Yay.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Oh, nice one.
Unknown: Finally.
DM: That was the goal.
Kenzo: Finally. Geez.
DM: And it's going to make, uh,
DM: three pseudo pod attacks.
Kenzo: Yep. Let's go.
DM: Uh, a one.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: The first one misses as it's-
Kenzo: Oh, that's only a one
DM: ... distracted by-
Kenzo: That means they roll this
DM: ... the second one is a 30 something.
Delwath: Yeah, AC is only 17.
DM: And the third is a 21.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So two hit.
DM: You're immune to acid?
Delwath: Yep, immune to acid, immune to poison, resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing.
DM: Uh, okay. So you take 20...
DM: 35 reduced by half.
Delwath: That's two hits.
DM: That's two hits.
Delwath: Yeah. I do have to make con saves.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, I have to make...
Delwath: So 35 reduced by 12.
Unknown: Well done.
DM: Sorry, that was... That's,
DM: that was the fir- that was the first hit, 35.
Delwath: The first hit was 35?
DM: 35 reduced by two.
Unknown: Okay. So what is that?
Unknown: 15-
Seeker: Oh, so we should be adding the temporary hit points of 328.
DM: Um, the second hit is 27.
Delwath: 15, that's okay.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: And the second hit is 27.
DM: 27, so it's 13.
Unknown: 13.
Seeker: So I have over 500 total now.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: That's okay.
Kenzo: It's just like massive like hit point.
DM: Um, and then it is going to, uh,
DM: shoot another...
DM: A line of acid can actually hit all four of you right now.
DM: So a line of acid is gonna erupt from right here and just fly out like
DM: in a straight line hitting all four of you.
DM: Everybody has to make a dex saving throw.
DM: Wellby and Kenzo with disadvantage.
DM: Wait, did you s- you didn't succeed, did you?
Wellby: No, I did not.
DM: Okay. So Wellby and Kenzo with disadvantage.
DM: Do I have to... Is this... Is there any...
Delwath: I'm also immune to restraint.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Sorry.
DM: [laughs] Okay.
Unknown: 19?
DM: What?
DM: 19 fails.
Unknown: 18.
DM: Fails.
Unknown: 18 fails.
Delwath: Is that the end of its turn?
DM: No, that's the end of its turn.
Unknown: Wait, do I, do I have to roll?
Unknown: No.
DM: No, 'cause it's acid damage.
DM: [laughs]
DM: It's acid and restraint.
Unknown: You're immune to acid.
DM: So you two both take 33 points of acid damage.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
Kenzo: Yeah, but also I'm resistant to it.
DM: Oh, you take half of that, so you take 16 points of acid damage.
DM: I will punch it again as a legendary.
Wellby: Uh, 33 is the half already?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: Oh, I'm also gonna do my legendary.
DM: Okay, so that's the end of his turn.
Delwath: Um, so 23 hits, right?
Wellby: [laughs] I'm at 28 hit points.
Unknown: I'm trying.
Delwath: Uh, 23 hits?
DM: 23 hits, yep.
Unknown: 2D12.
Delwath: That's better. 15, uh, plus 8, so 23.
Unknown: And then...
DM: Okay.
Seeker: And my slime attack
Unknown: is a s-
Unknown: 20
Seeker: ... 20. Misses.
DM: Uh, 20 mi- uh, 20 misses.
DM: No, 20 just hits.
Unknown: Oh, okay. I thought it was a miss.
DM: You have a 20. You've already rolled a 20, yeah.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You've only rolled a 19.
Delwath: 2D12 plus 8 bludgeoning.
Delwath: Uh, 13 plus 8, 21.
DM: So 21, and what was yours?
Delwath: I was also 21.
DM: Okay. So,
DM: um, more cracks begin to run along this, this tendril.
DM: Wait, uh, y- yeah, you should bonus action Healing Word on your next turn.
Wellby: That would be great.
Unknown: So Kenzo's up.
DM: No, on your last turn.
Delwath: Oh, you can't cast two level spells.
Kenzo: What's my deal again now 'cause I'm restrained?
DM: So disadvantage on all attacks.
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: Your move is zero.
Kenzo: That's fine. And then I can try to-
DM: At the end of your turn you get another dex save to escape.
Seeker: I always forget Healing Word. All right.
DM: And remember, it attacks whoever attacked it last.
Kenzo: That's fine. I want it to attack me.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: All right. Uh, so disadvantage.
Delwath: Wait, where is it? It wasn't attacking me before.
DM: Kenzo, Wellby, Seeker, Dalwath, then it.
DM: It's first.
Kenzo: Oh, man. I rolled 20 and a 2, so that misses, right?
DM: That misses.
Kenzo: 17 misses.
Unknown: Fuck, I rolled a one.
DM: Misses.
Unknown: Damn it.
DM: Your... As you try and get it with your staff, the like acid net around you is holding you back.
Kenzo: First arm strike.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: It's at 20 AC. You don't have a plus 16, do you?
Kenzo: I do not. Fuck.
DM: That misses.
Kenzo: Disadvantage sucks.
Unknown: It does.
Unknown: All right, that hits.
DM: That hits.
Unknown: All right.
DM: You gotta beat these saves.
Kenzo: Hold on. Then, hold on. And then the last one, um,
Kenzo: that also hits. All right, so two hit.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So I do-
Unknown: So 2D12 plus 2D6.
Kenzo: No, uh, 3D12.
Unknown: No, the... You have-
Kenzo: I, I get to spend an extra D12 on any of them.
DM: He gets an extra D12 on any-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... first attack that hits.
Kenzo: Right. Right, right, right. 3D12, 2D6 plus 10.
DM: And this is force damage?
Kenzo: Force damage, yeah.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: I can, I can make it force damage.
Delwath: There's no way it can be resistant to force damage.
Kenzo: Oh, pl- uh, plus 14.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Plus 14.
Unknown: Oh, that's good.
Kenzo: 22, 25,
Kenzo: 29 plus 14.
Unknown: Kenzo's really like...
DM: How much?
Kenzo: Uh.
DM: 29 plus 14.
Unknown: 43.
DM: And that's all fours?
Kenzo: Yep, all fours. Yeah.
Kenzo: That's only with two hits.
DM: Like four big cracks spread along
DM: this- ...
DM: tendril here.
DM: It's not, it's not quite, you know,
DM: broken but...
DM: Still resistant to bludgeoning.
DM: [laughs] That, uh...
DM: So make your dex save to try and break free.
Unknown: Bitch.
Unknown: Come on, bitch. Ah.
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: It's finicky.
Unknown: Reroll.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Thank you. That's gotta, that's gotta work.
Unknown: 25.
DM: That works.
DM: It is still gonna attack you, though.
Unknown: That's fine.
DM: Without advantage this time, but it's legendary at the end of your turn.
DM: That, ah, that's a one.
Delwath: The big giant monsters are really rolling poorly.
DM: I know. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Ken's, Ken's-
Delwath: All of, all of us, yeah
DM: ... So it is Wellby's turn.
Unknown: Ugh.
DM: Or unless anybody wants legendaries.
Delwath: I used them up. Well, I can move.
Unknown: I-
Wellby: I'm, I'm done too.
Delwath: Okay. 'Cause the slam is two legendaries.
DM: I see.
Delwath: So we can only do one slam.
DM: One slam,
DM: uh...
Delwath: And there's not really a point in moving.
Wellby: I can probably survive one more hit.
Wellby: Uh, I will shoot its-
DM: Have you been rolling to see if your tidal wave recharges on your turns?
Delwath: Oh, I'd forgotten. I don't...
Unknown: Actually...
Delwath: Roll a D6 to see if your tidal wave...
Unknown: Well, you haven't used it yet.
Wellby: I haven't used it.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Is this one of three of these we have to beat, or is this the one we have to beat?
DM: We don't know.
Kenzo: I think this is one of three. Well, for sure we're gonna have to fight something in the well.
Kenzo: This is, this is... We may be able to avoid the other one, but...
Kenzo: This is the small one. Yeah, yeah.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Uh, okay. Well, I will shoot it then.
Wellby: Um, that's a
Wellby: 23 or something like that.
Unknown: Miss. Yeah, that's a 20, so you miss.
Wellby: 4, 8,
Wellby: 9.
Unknown: It's, it's an axe strike.
Wellby: Uh...
Wellby: Doesn't really the D6 go here?
DM: No, Seeker and Delwath are next.
Unknown: Oh, we're next.
DM: It's Wellby's turn. It's very difficult to keep, keep track of the turn order with-
Unknown: I know
Wellby: ... this many legendary actions.
Wellby: 10, that's not great. 15, 22, 31 damage and then I will bonus action drink my last potion of
Wellby: s- a small amount of heal- of greater healing.
Unknown: 2d4s.
Wellby: Yep.
DM: Uh, that ends your turn?
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: yep.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Is that, that... Oh, and I roll, uh...
DM: To escape.
Wellby: Nope.
DM: It's going to attack you
DM: with its legendary action.
DM: Uh, that's a...
DM: That hits.
Wellby: Awesome.
Wellby: Oops.
DM: So you take 18 bludgeoning plus eight acid.
Delwath: Can't you uncanny dodge?
Wellby: No, 'cause I'm restrained.
DM: Oh.
Wellby: I assume I can't uncanny dodge when I'm restrained.
DM: Uh...
Wellby: Unless I can.
DM: I think... I mean, yeah, you...
DM: There's nothing that said... You just have, you have disadvantage on dex saving throws.
Delwath: Unless uncanny dodge requires you to have speed.
DM: I don't think uncann- Does uncanny dodge say you can't use it if your speed is zero?
Unknown: Let me look.
DM: I know that Ken's...
DM: That the dodge action is you can't use it if your speed is zero.
Unknown: [laughs] Uncanny dodge.
Kenzo: Dude, Kenzo's really unkillable.
Wellby: Yeah, no, she reacted.
Kenzo: I also have, like, my, my, my, uh...
DM: Yeah, okay. So yeah, you can use it.
Wellby: All right. So that's n- uh, what was the total damage?
DM: The... It was 18 and 6, so 20...
Unknown: 20-
DM: ... 4.
Unknown: Great.
Wellby: So 12 damage.
Unknown: 24 to 12.
DM: Uh, that's its l- [laughs] legendary action.
DM: You're still restrained.
DM: You should actually be rolling all these...
DM: I forgot 'cause you're restrained, you have disadvantage on dex, so you should be rolling the saves to escape with disadvantage.
Unknown: Oh, that's rough.
Wellby: Really?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Did I have disadvantage to escape?
DM: It's pretty nasty to be restrained because...
DM: I mean, might have ways to get out of...
DM: I mean,
DM: Delwath has, like, 10 ways to get out of restraints.
Wellby: Yeah, all sorts of magical ways.
Delwath: But also is currently, uh, in water element form.
Unknown: And immune to restraints [laughs].
DM: And immune to restraint.
Wellby: Uh, it doesn't really matter 'cause I've failed them all anyway, so...
DM: Yeah, exactly. It's Seeker's turn.
DM: Uh...
Delwath: You might just Leviathan smash it and heal Wellby.
DM: Oh.
Wellby: Sure.
Unknown: That's a good idea.
Kenzo: That very first save. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: As Kong said...
DM: [laughs] It's true.
Kenzo: Yeah. You're like, "Well, just, just see what happens."
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I assumed it was just damage.
Wellby: It was not just damage.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Um, I cast a healing word at
DM: 5th level.
DM: So that's 1d-
Kenzo: It's so crazy how, like, like, saving throws are just, like, the most important thing actually.
DM: Yeah. 10d4 plus
DM: 5.
Unknown: Just roll that on there.
DM: 10d4 plus 5.
Kenzo: Oh, that's a lot of d4s.
Seeker: Yeah. Uh, it's 29.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: Awesome.
DM: And...
Wellby: That more than doubles my hit points.
Seeker: Amazing. And then, uh-
Delwath: I mean, you can take your full attacks.
Delwath: You can attack twice if you-
Seeker: So, like, the multi-attack is a slam and a tail?
Delwath: A slam and a tail, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, they're both plus 14 to hit.
Kenzo: Both plus 14. One you're slamming, one you're dancing.
DM: Uh, I mean body or tail. The tail has, like, four large cracks in it.
Unknown: Tail.
DM: Tail.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Oh, nice.
Seeker: 18 and an 18.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So 32 and 33.
Delwath: 2d10, 2d10 plus 2d12.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Plus 16.
Kenzo: Nice. We love this.
Seeker: Now we're ta- now we're talking, Levi.
Kenzo: Love this.
DM: Oh and wow, not a good roll.
DM: Oh my God.
Seeker: Oh, kind of good. You know what I'm saying?
Seeker: 14 plus 7 is 21 plus...
Delwath: Plus 16.
DM: Is 37.
Unknown: 37.
DM: Nice.
Delwath: 37 bludgeoning-
DM: Not terrible
Unknown: ... from two big fists.
DM: No, a fist and a tail.
Delwath: A fist and a tail.
Delwath: Oh, Delwath's tidal breath recharges.
DM: Uh...
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I'm just gonna sit here.
Unknown: Well... [laughs]
DM: Okay, um, two more big cracks appear and it
DM: roars up and launches a massive punch at Seeker.
Unknown: Yay.
DM: That's a 19.
DM: So that... Uh, sorry, a 19 on the dex.
Delwath: It's a four... Uh, these guys don't have great AC.
Unknown: 17.
Unknown: I see.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You take 14 points of bludgeoning and zero points of acid from the pseudopod.
Seeker: So with, with resistance to bludgeoning?
Delwath: It's 14 already after now.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: So seven.
Delwath: So seven.
Seeker: Uh, so I take seven off of my 328.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: But you, but you do have to make a constitution
Unknown: save.
Unknown: [coughs] Oh, shit. Yeah.
Delwath: That's okay. You only have to roll a...
Delwath: Actually, you can't fail.
DM: Do they have... What do they have, plus?
Unknown: 10.
DM: So you can't fail. You don't have to make a con save.
Unknown: Wait, why does that-
DM: 'Cause if you roll a one, it's 11, and you only have to beat a 10.
Seeker: Because of the constitution-
Delwath: The con is plus 10
Seeker: ... of the leviathan.
Delwath: Of the leviathan. It has to do-
Unknown: See, that seems critical [laughs].
Delwath: It has to do more-
Unknown: That's pretty scary
Delwath: ... Oh, that's a good point. It has to do more than 22 damage for you have to roll a con save.
DM: Which is tough when you're-
Delwath: Your resistance
Unknown: ... this.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay, uh-
Unknown: It's a good combo.
Unknown: That was a legendary.
Unknown: Yeah, it's great.
Delwath: So Delweth is up. Okay, Delweth's turn.
Delwath: I'm gonna, I'm gonna tidal wave again.
Unknown: Now-
Kenzo: Why aren't you tidal waving?
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: Spells are better.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Delweth can't cast spells. I can cast spells.
Unknown: Ah, got it, got it.
Seeker: And it's, and it's a strength save, and also it's gonna hit everybody.
Delwath: It's very good at strength. No, I just make it right h- the, you're still flying, right?
Kenzo: I don't know if we're still flying.
Delwath: Well, I'll make the-
Unknown: I'm gonna do-
Delwath: I'll make the tidal wave appear here and go that way.
Delwath: There we go. That's great.
Unknown: That you can do.
Unknown: It's great.
Seeker: Oh, right. I think I misread it at first.
Seeker: You can make it small if you want to.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So, so it's not too big.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Tidal wave.
DM: So that's a strength save?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: d34 strength save.
Delwath: I mean, d34 is a little bit tough, even if it's a plus 10.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Uh, yeah, it rolled a two.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: So that's only a 16.
Kenzo: Started out not being super, super psyched about the, uh, the Kenzo in a big mask.
Kenzo: It's my favorite. It's my favorite Kenzo.
Unknown: I mean, it is his design.
Delwath: Yeah, so 7d12.
Seeker: He popped his collar and it was so [laughs].
Unknown: [laughs] I didn't do that, but it's the script.
Unknown: That's 5d12.
Kenzo: When he's attacking he switches his faces and pops
Unknown: his, pops his-
Unknown: 10, 22, 32-
Unknown: He's angry now [laughs]
Delwath: ... 38 plus
Delwath: 8 is, uh, 46.
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry. It's gonna use the legendary resistance, so half of 46.
Unknown: [sighs] Uh...
Wellby: Wait, what's the pseudopod situation?
Unknown: [whooshes]
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Does it like wash away in the tidal wave?
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Great.
Unknown: And the ooze
DM: begins to bubble
Unknown: and split apart. [growls]
Kenzo: I just add effects.
Unknown: As
DM: with that blast...
DM: I made it too strong.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It falls to pieces and begins to drain away, crystallizing and hardening as you hit it.
Unknown: Oh, nice.
Unknown: Awesome.
DM: And there is a rumbling sound.
Unknown: No.
Wellby: Rumbling.
Kenzo: No rumbling.
DM: And the earth begins to shake.
Unknown: What?
Seeker: And we, we, uh-
Unknown: And what do you do?
Wellby: We go take a long rest [laughs].
Unknown: [laughs] Uh...
Seeker: Do you Leviathan?
Wellby: Well, uh, can I get out of the...
Wellby: I assume the-
Unknown: You're not restrained
Wellby: ... condition that's on me?
Unknown: Yeah, it, um-
Unknown: Oh, actual- wow [laughs].
DM: It actually hardens into crystal.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: Kenzo goes over and breaks out-
Unknown: Little help? Little help?
Kenzo: ... breaks out the, the, the-
DM: Uh, yeah, but that's...
DM: Let me keep track of how long these things take you.
DM: Um, so anybody can free either one of them with a, with automatically with a help action, or you can break out as an action.
Delwath: Well, can I use a, like your action to break them out?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Sure. You can wash it away.
Delwath: I have a 27 strength.
DM: Yes. Yes, yes, yes.
Delwath: A big... The, the, the r- river comes and swooshes it away.
Delwath: Swooshes across you, dissolving the acid with it.
Unknown: [sighs]
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Ah.
Delwath: The crystal, taking the crystal.
Wellby: Refreshing.
Seeker: With the swoosh of your giant flipper.
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: Wait, could you have done that when it was acid?
Unknown: No.
Wellby: That would've been nice.
DM: It... This is just a, this is just a color.
Wellby: All right.
DM: There's no mechanism for somebody to help you break out of-
Wellby: Got it
DM: ... being restrained in this case.
Unknown: Sometimes there are-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... but this particular-
Wellby: Yeah
Unknown: ... one,
DM: no. So, um-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... you can, you can hear in the distance like a faint cracking, crumbling sound, like stones and earth falling.
Unknown: Go towards it.
Delwath: I don't know. I'm not very smart.
Wellby: Uh...
Kenzo: How long does the leviathan last?
Unknown: That way.
Wellby: Little bit of-
Unknown: Holy shit
Wellby: ... little bit of healing?
Delwath: Delweth's going towards it [laughs].
Wellby: Healing?
Delwath: I guess I'll wait if every, if nobody is following.
Unknown: Delweth will turn.
Wellby: Healing? You don't have magic.
Unknown: No.
Wellby: More healing?
Seeker: I can cast another healing spell on you guys.
Delwath: Uh, you used your ninth level slot.
Delwath: This is where, um, power heal would sort of be helpful.
Seeker: Yeah, but I...
Unknown: But you're a leviathan.
Kenzo: Wish I could give you some, uh,
Kenzo: some healing stuff.
Wellby: Thanks. Thanks.
Kenzo: I gave you my p- my potion.
Wellby: Oh, you did. You did.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I c- I could do another fifth level healing word.
Delwath: Do you have... You don't have a q- you don't have any other cures, do you?
Wellby: I'm gaining a new appreciation for Tenzo's role as the person who just soaks up damage.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, right?
Wellby: Very different thing than he was doing.
Kenzo: I mean, dude, I'm so good at it now too, 'cause I have, I have the, the, that boon of healing thing I got.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: I have 10, I have 10 hit dice I can use as a bonus action.
Wellby: Wow.
Kenzo: 10, 10d10. A, I have a pool of 10d10s I can just roll whenever I want to gain a little bit of hit points.
Wellby: I have one more 10d10, so I can wait.
Delwath: Um, I'm wondering if I should turn back into Delweth.
Unknown: Eh.
Unknown: We'll see. I won't do it yet.
Kenzo: Well, the next thing is the, uh-
Seeker: All right. I'm gonna do the healing word, right?
Kenzo: I mean, we still got an hour.
Wellby: I can use another healing word.
Kenzo: 'Cause I... The ooze is still gonna be the same thing.
Wellby: It's gonna be a 10, four plus-
Kenzo: So this has been very useful from, uh-
Kenzo: 10, four plus five
Kenzo: ... yeah. Oh, I got a plus here.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: 32.
Wellby: Yeah, that's-
Kenzo: Being like essentially immune to the whole bit
Wellby: ... that is something cracked.
Kenzo: Been very useful.
Unknown: Fuck. Uh,
Kenzo: well, 'cause the river connects into the cistern, right?
Kenzo: Does that close in there somehow?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Can we follow the tendril?
Unknown: Wow.
Delwath: Well, you washed it away.
Kenzo: Well, I know, but the tendril was-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah
Kenzo: ... reaching into-
Unknown: It's crystallized
Kenzo: ... you know, it's crystallized.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Let- let's follow the crystal tendril.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Let's see where it leads.
Seeker: What, are we still... Are we going into the ash storm?
DM: Yeah, you're, you're in the ash.
DM: You're, right now you're in the ash storm.
DM: The visibility is only 30 feet
Kenzo: But everybody's immune to all the stuff.
Wellby: Yes.
Seeker: If as long as we s- we have to stay leviathans.
Delwath: No, no. Here's Feast makes you immune to poison.
Seeker: Oh, Here's Feast makes immune to poison.
Kenzo: Yeah. Let's, uh, let's follow the river. Let's stay in the river.
Kenzo: Let's, 'cause while you guys are still leviathans, let's, let's, let's flow, let's flow with the, with the-
Delwath: Is there, like, another connection from the river that this was feeding through?
Kenzo: Into the cistern.
Delwath: Into the cistern?
DM: Uh, wait, hold on.
DM: What do you mean?
DM: Like-
Kenzo: We- we're leaving at 4:30?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Where...
DM: So along the river was there...
Delwath: We're wondering where the cistern was fed from the river.
Delwath: Like, is there a spot along the river where the cistern would've been fed?
DM: Uh,
DM: at the moment, n- I mean, anything that w- did used to connect them has collapsed.
Delwath: But is there, like, a... So there's not really a,
Delwath: there's not really a spot. So to follow the tendril would be over land, follow the tendril towards the-
DM: It's over land, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: 'Cause we're only going to the well.
DM: That's the direction it's heading, yeah.
Kenzo: Let's just fucking go to the well.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, that's where, where this has all gotta go anyways, right?
Kenzo: We gotta go down into the, into the well, down into the fucking-
Wellby: Yeah, but could conceivably if we go to the well, if there's still two of these out there and one of them's in the well-
Delwath: We might have to fight two
Wellby: ... we wanna fight the other one not in the well so that we only have to fight one in the well.
Kenzo: Good point. Good point.
Delwath: Can Kenzo
Kenzo: do his rogue action?
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Te- Tim, what's going on?
DM: Yeah, that's an action.
DM: Um, you have this, you've done it once before so it takes a ki, but I think you have plenty of ki left.
Kenzo: I do. And, and next time we roll-
DM: And roll initiative you'll get it back
Unknown: ... roll initiative, I'll get it back, yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, there never was three-
Kenzo: Yeah, but just, but just the, the concentration, is it, is it still those two?
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Is where, where are they basically?
DM: Uh, everything is centered on the well right now.
Kenzo: Great. Let's go to the well.
Wellby: Let's go to the well.
Seeker: So it's sort of retracting.
DM: Yeah, that's what it is.
Kenzo: So it's gonna be like a fucking 2,000 hit point.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs] Do you have any more healing potions hanging around?
Kenzo: I'll give you whatever I have, yeah.
Unknown: Oh, I have-
Wellby: I've used my other-
Seeker: I have one but it's inside my blubber.
DM: [laughs] I have one but it's also-
Kenzo: It's inside my blubber.
DM: We're not r- but no, we're made of water.
DM: You're, but you're-
Unknown: I know, leviathan-
Delwath: ... leviathan's a w- I know. The leviathan's a water elemental.
Unknown: I didn't know that.
Seeker: Oh, I have a four-
Delwath: That's why it can get, it, it can go through a space as small-
Unknown: I have four potions of greater healing
DM: ... as small as an inch 'cause it-
Wellby: Can I get two of those?
Unknown: Yeah, of course.
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... because it's, it's a, it's a sea serpent, but it's shaped of wa-
Unknown: That's, uh-
DM: It's actually a water elemental is what the monster is
Kenzo: ... 44 plus four. 44 plus four, so it's 8d4 plus eight.
DM: [coughs]
Kenzo: 8d4 plus eight.
Wellby: All right, 27. Good, that gets me back to-
Kenzo: I, dude, why don't you take the last two?
Kenzo: We're not gonna rest again until-
Wellby: Yeah, but what if, like, uh-
Kenzo: Keep a couple for-
Wellby: Yeah. All right.
Unknown: For, for what?
DM: Oh, you can-
Wellby: Oh, to keep it full
Delwath: ... I, I, but maybe don't use them all.
DM: He can burn his action to look at the tendril.
Delwath: Oh, well why not, actually? No reason not to.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I'll keep one more just in case, like-
Unknown: Dude, I'll give you a-
Wellby: ... I'm the last person surviving
Kenzo: ... I'll give you the other two that I have, and you can drink a way, drink them whenever you want.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: All right?
Wellby: I'm gonna drink one now and keep one.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So you rush forward.
Wellby: Great. Very good. I'm gonna do that.
DM: Running towards the,
DM: uh-
DM: With these two water creatures following
DM: ... with these two water creatures following, running towards the,
DM: um,
DM: the center.
DM: You break out through the storm, and you see that the center of this plaza has partially collapsed.
DM: And in the center
DM: is, like, a 400-foot long ooze.
Unknown: What?
Wellby: Whoa.
Kenzo: Wait, th- this is not the well. This is, this is-
DM: No, the cen-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... the plaza has collapsed.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: So it's a slope down.
Wellby: Into the cistern.
Delwath: Into the well.
DM: Into the cistern.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: And emerging out of it is this massive...
DM: Not sure actually that battle maps are gonna be that useful here.
Unknown: Come on.
DM: This thing, this is, like-
Kenzo: I'm into the Lego battle map
DM: ... 400 feet across.
Wellby: Are we in the eye of the storm right now where it's not-
DM: You've just emerged out from the eye of the storm.
DM: And it's, like, it's writhing, like-
Unknown: Hey, hey
DM: ... in anger.
Kenzo: Um, you, you took my staff.
DM: [coughs] Looming-
Unknown: Watch the step
DM: ... like, bits of it looming up, grabbing, um-
Wellby: Do you wanna counterbalance?
Unknown: Uh,
Kenzo: I'm seeing if there's a way to add this into the staff.
DM: Put it at the, you'd have to put it at the bottom.
Unknown: Oh, that's true. Let's try that.
DM: [laughs] Yeah, you can thread that, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: It's stuck. [laughs]
Kenzo: All right. Now we're talking.
Kenzo: [laughs] I've just got a new staff.
Seeker: [laughs] All right, all right, all right.
Kenzo: Okay. [laughs] Now we're, now we're getting somewhere.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay, so.
Unknown: Oh, shit. [laughs]
DM: You rush forward, you emerge out of the storm of ash, and you see this,
DM: like, collaps- collapsed plaza.
DM: So it, like, slopes down. There's, like, a gradient slope down to the bottom.
DM: And at the... So just the, like, ring of the plaza is still stable.
DM: You still see those columns and the, and the, like, partial cover of the fallen, um [laughs] of the fallen,
DM: uh, of the fallen market, but this, towards the river the entire ground has collapsed, and it just slopes down to the bottom of this cistern at which there's this m- like, just
DM: utterly enormous roiling mass of multicolored ooze bubbling and raging and beginning to climb out and rush
DM: towards, towards you.
Delwath: Can we, is there, like, um...
Delwath: Is there still, like, the
Delwath: center down there somewhere thing that we saw earlier?
Delwath: Can we tell?
DM: You can't see it.
Unknown: It's probably not on-
DM: It's definitely inside the ooze
Delwath: So we have to fight our way through the ooze to that magical nodule.
Delwath: It probably has, like, basically infinite hit points.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: The nodule or this thing?
Delwath: Yeah, the nodule. We probably have to find the nodule.
Wellby: [coughs] Uh, I c- I can Arrow of Discovery the nodule.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, I think we should stop here though because it's 4:15.
DM: We could take a few minutes to do a little bit of dinner prep and then go see the sunset.
Unknown: Sounds like a plan.
DM: Yeah, 'cause I don't wanna, like, just...
DM: I mean, you're gonna roll initiative as the first thing we do.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Totally, totally, totally.
Seeker: How are we gonna fight something so large?
Seeker: This is ridiculous. I like it.
Unknown: I,
Delwath: I suspect our strategy is gonna be...
Delwath: It probably has effectively unlimited hit points.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So I doubt it's mechanically useful to just try and, like, kill the various little bits, right?
Delwath: We probably have to get to the...
Unknown: the-
Seeker: So as leviathans, we can swim through it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I guess.
Unknown: [coughs] I mean...
Wellby: It's easier through water.
Seeker: Is the, is the nodule thing...
Wellby: Like, we could, I don't know, force cage it and then-
Unknown: The nodule?
Wellby: ... with ourselves on the inside with the nodule to keep the rest of the leviathan out maybe?
Unknown: How far down is the nodule? I mean-
Wellby: Or the rest of the ooze out
DM: ... it's, it's, like, in the middle.
DM: Like, it's in the middle of this bubbling mass of ooze, right?
Kenzo: The... It's in the middle of this.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: This thing.
Kenzo: I, I don't... I think, I think we might just have to, like, do, like, a couple thousand points of damage.
Delwath: Well, I think, I think Seeker and I as leviathans should, like, head towards the nodule.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right?
Kenzo: I mean, sure. I can go... I can join you guys.
Kenzo: I'm an astral being.
Wellby: I can hang out at a safe distance [laughs].
Seeker: You'll soak up the damage [laughs].
Unknown: Soak... I'll just soak up the damage.
Kenzo: Yeah, you stay, you stay at the top.
Wellby: I'll take the... I'll take the hits.
Kenzo: Just shoot it some arrows.
Kenzo: Hit it with some arrows.
Seeker: [laughs] You're our tank today.
Delwath: Like, that seems like maybe the right move is to try and move through the mass towards the nodule.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But, um, what do we do to the nodule once we find it?
Kenzo: I like this, uh, this collaborative activity.
Unknown: Well, I guess we'll decide when we get there.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Force cage is not a crazy idea.
DM: What would force cage accomplish?
DM: L- nothing whatsoever at all.
Unknown: We could-
DM: It would just make it harder for you to destroy it.
Wellby: If we were on the inside though, we could keep the rest of the leviathan...
Delwath: Yeah. No, that's true.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But it's probably not that useful because...
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But maybe we could... It would buy us time to do imprisonment or something like that.
Unknown: Oh, wow, this is gonna be good.
Delwath: Or we just destroy it somehow.
Unknown: Banish it.
Seeker: Or destroy it somehow.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: I mean, maybe if we just attack it.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: Sure.
Wellby: The nodule thing is a part of it.
Wellby: It's not, like, a...
Unknown: It's a part.
Wellby: It's not like something that's inside. It's like an organ or something.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So I mean, we could try and just cut our way to the...
Delwath: Like, cut a path to the nodule kind of.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] So
Kenzo: s- so don't... Keep talking. Don't pay attention to me [laughs].
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: This, this is the group photo that we all, we all really wanted [laughs].
Unknown: Everybody on Kenzo's...
Unknown: [laughs] Okay.
Unknown: That's a little silly.
DM: Um, what was our dinner plans for tonight?
Kenzo: Stop being silly.
Unknown: We are being silly.
Unknown: Chicken,
Unknown: mushrooms-